Friends, in this video we will
discuss about two wheeler insurance and
what points will we discuss in this video, let's
first look at all those things, first of all
we will discuss what is
first party insurance which is
also called comprehensive insurance
and similarly what is our third
party insurance, similarly we will
see what is called second party insurance,
apart from all this there is a term
which we call zero dept or zero
depreciation, what is this term,
along with this we will see what is personal
accident cover,
we will see all these terms in this video, along with this at the
end of this video when
we understand everything first,
then at the end of the video I will also do the live insurance of my two
wheeler, my scooter which is active at home, and
tell you how we can do it in less than 1 minute, that is,
two wheeler
insurance is so easy that in
less than 1 minute we can do
two wheeler
insurance sitting at home  Now
what is the problem? Normally, if we talk about India,
most people are afraid. The first thing you
should know is what is first
party, second party, third
party, zero depreciation? These are very basic
things. I will explain it to you in this video.
Even a fifth-grade student watching it will
understand. It's so easy. What
I mean to say is that in India,
what happens is that most people go to a shop near their house that does
insurance,
etc., and say, "
Yes, the insurance for the car has expired, the
insurance for the bike has expired." So,
whatever it is, he does the insurance for you.
Now, what is the problem?
You go to that shopkeeper and say, "
Okay, get me the insurance." The person who is
doing the insurance is not doing it out of his own pocket
or doing it himself. He will do it himself.
He also goes online and gets the
insurance for you in a minute.
Tell me, have you ever gone to get insurance? Did
he take more than a minute? You have to
enter a couple of things. He does the
insurance for you. Now, believe
him.  Let's assume that you had a scooter,
for example, he insured it online, it cost
him ₹6600. If you had done it yourself
sitting at home, it would have taken less than a minute. It would have cost
you ₹6600 too, but he
generates a bill for you, sometimes for ₹800, sometimes for ₹. Meaning, have
you ever thought that you are giving him ₹3300 every time
unnecessarily. It is possible that he makes someone's insured for ₹
1100, for someone for ₹1000, that is,
you are giving him unnecessarily money.
Just because if you understand these two-three
things in 2 minutes, then for any
lifetime, whenever you have any two-wheeler at your home,
you can insure it in 2 minutes. It is
that easy, so let's
understand it here and then do it live.
All the things will take us less than a minute.
Let's first understand everything here.
Okay, yes, first of all, if
I talk about what is our first party
insurance, which we call
comprehensive insurance.  They also say,
look, suppose this is your two-wheeler, okay,
you are going, suppose any
vehicle comes in front, let's suppose anything is coming,
you have an accident with the vehicle, it is our
fault, our vehicle got damaged, the
vehicle of the person in front also got damaged, if
I have first party insurance, okay, then it
means that
whatever damage is caused to my vehicle, as well as
whatever damage is caused to the person in front,
my insurance
company will bear all the money, that is,
my expenses as well as the
expenses of the person in front will be borne by my insurance company,
if I have first party insurance,
if I have third part insurance,
only third part insurance, then
in that case, suppose this is our two-wheeler,
okay, any
vehicle was coming from the front, we suffered a loss, it was
my fault, the vehicle in front also got destroyed,
our vehicle also got destroyed, so
in this case, because I have only third
party insurance, that is,
who is the third party, anyone in front, I do
not have my insurance, that is, first  If the
party is not insured then in this case
whatever loss will be incurred because it was my fault then
my insurance company will
bear whatever expenses the other party has to bear but the loss that I suffered,
I got hurt on the bike or
Activa, if anyone got hurt then
my insurance company will not bear that loss,
who is called the second party, whatever our
insurance company is, it is
called the second party, so this is the main difference between
first party, second party and third
party, now there is one more thing, this first
party is what we
call comprehensive insurance, so I explained to you earlier that
like let's suppose someone has
first part insurance and he
collided his car in a way, the car got damaged,
our car also got damaged, the other car
also got damaged, now if I have first
part insurance then it does not mean that if the
expense is ₹1000000 then our
insurance company will give us ₹1000000. Comprehensive
insurance means what we call first party
insurance, it means that
if suppose any metal part gets damaged then
100% of it  You will get the full amount.
Whatever metal damage has occurred
inside the vehicle, you will get 100% of it. But if suppose
any plastic part is damaged, you will
get money for that only at 50%. If there is any
damage to glass etc., you will get money for that also at
50%. And if there is any damage to rubbers etc. tyres etc., then you will
get money for that only at 50%. Now a question will
arise that yes, we have heard many times
that when a vehicle, i.e. two wheeler etc. gets
damaged and is insured, then
just go and park the vehicle in the agency, there is
only one file charge of ₹ 600 up to
₹ 1 and after that,
if there is insurance, then you get the full
claim. How do you get that?
See, we call it zero depreciation.
Look, here I have attached screenshots of
all of them. All of them are fine. This is comprehensive.
I explained to you, first party and third
party. Similarly, this is an add-on
which is called zero depreciation. When you
select it here, it  By the way, the
entire interface of Policy Bazaar is very
good. Policy Bazaar's interface is very good. Right from
here, let me explain to you how we can get insurance
for ourselves in less than 1 minute.
And the good thing about
Policy Bazaar is that
as you can see here, you have
more than 20 different companies. You
can compare insurance companies in a minute. Suppose
you just have to enter your act number or
whatever bike number you have, that's it.
Whatever the registered number is,
Activa-i is ₹
717, IIC Lombard is ₹7731.
United India
is giving the same insurance for ₹760. By doing this, you
can compare more than 20 companies
in one click. I will
explain it to you in the end. What I mean to say is that
as you see this interface, from here, suppose
if you want to take zero depreciation also, then
select this add-on, the
rate will increase a little, for example, IIC
Lombard is ₹  7731 is running okay it is
showing without zero depreciation of
first part insurance as
soon as you select zero depreciation
its rate will increase a little it will come around ₹ by the way
what does zero depreciation mean see zero depreciation
means that now if our car gets hit
okay it was our mistake the person in front hit us we suffered a
loss he also suffered a loss so
now what do we have to do, just
take our car to the agency and park it
there only one file charge will be ₹ 800
okay sir just for preparing the file that this
accident has happened to the car
whatever expenses will be incurred after that we do
n't need to pay even a rupee from our pocket this is the benefit
of zero depreciation so there should
definitely be zero depreciation but there are
some points of zero depreciation till
when can you avail zero depreciation until
your vehicle is not older than 5 years once
your  If the vehicle is more than 5 years old,
you cannot take zero depreciation. Did
you understand the meaning? Then you will
not get zero depreciation. No
insurance company will give you the zero depreciation
feature if your vehicle is more than 5 years
old. Second thing, suppose your
vehicle is not more than 5 years old, okay, and
you have taken zero depreciation, then suppose
this year is going on, your bike met with an
accident, you took a zero
depreciation claim, okay, now this
year the bike got damaged again, there was another
accident, the bike got destroyed,
you said there is zero depreciation, okay, the
company will say, okay, no charge will be
taken, take this, take the full claim. Now suppose it happens for the
third time this year, then you will
not get any claim, that is, the maximum zero
depreciation claim can be given only twice a year.
okay, so these were all the
things about zero depreciation,
okay, rest of the policy is available in the market, this
zero depreciation feature  You get
this as well, now there
is road side assistance on Policy Bazaar. Road side
assistance
means that if suppose your
bike breaks down somewhere, Activa-i
vehicle, then all these features are available just by making a
call to your insurance company or
on Policy Bazaar also, their assistance is available 24*7 so that
we do not need to take much headache,
so this is also a very good feature, all the road
side
assistance are written, whatever
they are, that is, if anyone gets it
renewed, suppose every year we get
our bike or two
wheeler insurance renewed, then if anyone gets it
renewed, then
we
also get a discount of approximately up to 80-85 on Policy Bazaar, that is,
if I talk about these Policy Bazaar, then
approximately, their
insurance for two wheeler starts from ₹ 75,
if I say in terms of per day, then from ₹
1.30 paise to ₹ 30  Their insurance starts on the basis of money per day,
okay, let's
see after that, one more thing is very important for you to
see, we call it IDV i.e.
Insured Declared Value, it means
that I now have a two wheeler, okay,
I also get it insured on my own,
let's assume that we have learnt
what first party insurance is, okay,
what is third party, we have also seen zero debt
that we should take it, now the question
comes that first of all he will ask what is IDV, what
is IDV i.e. Insured Declared
Value, what is the value of how much vehicle,
what value do you put, so in this case, to
put the value of the vehicle, first thing
look here for a second, on the main
interface, you will see the
insured value here, for example, my
Activa-i, this is a 2019 model, okay, so it has
put a price of ₹ 600, okay, that means
it had taken it on its own, but if I
want, I can increase or decrease the price myself,
okay, IDV  I
can increase or decrease the price myself, right? Now let's
assume how the price of IDV is
ideally set, so it is a simple
thing, let's assume I bought a vehicle for ₹1
lakh, okay, this is its ex-
showroom price, okay, yes, on top of this, suppose there is
registration cost, its
insurance is also there, suppose the registration
cost is 0000, let's say the insurance is of
000, it will not be 15, let's say it is 1 lakh, then it becomes
10000, so suppose this vehicle cost
me ₹130000 on road, okay,
but what is its ex-showroom price, it is
₹1 lakh, right? So, above ₹1 lakh, I
will also set the IDV, that is, the value of the vehicle which will be
accepted by the company, or suppose the person from whom we are getting the
insurance done will accept only ₹1 lakh, otherwise
we got the insurance done, got the
registration done, this is an extra expense,
now the question arises that when I am getting the vehicle
insured, then how should I calculate the value, suppose
My vehicle is absolutely fresh right now
and is less than 6 months old,
its age is 1 to 6 months, if the
vehicle is 6 months old then deduct its value by 5,
I have to get insurance for that much, that is, I have
bought a completely fresh vehicle for 1 lakh, so declare its value as 95000,
okay, now suppose you did
not get the insurance done or for some
reason you have to get it done from another company,
and the vehicle is from 6 months to 1 year
old, then deduct 15 from the amount for which the vehicle was purchased,
that is its value, that is
1 lakh, its showroom price,
deduct 15, that is its value, that is,
if the vehicle is 6 months to 1 year old,
similarly, if the vehicle is from 1 year to 2 years
old, then deduct its value by 20,
if any vehicle is from 1 year
to 2 years old, then select its ID as
80000 and enter
your value according to 80000  Calculate the value of the vehicle and
take insurance accordingly. Similarly, suppose if
someone's vehicle is 3 to 4 years old,
sorry, it is 2 to 3 years old, then
deduct the value of the vehicle by 30%. If it is 3 to 4 years old, then
deduct it by 40%. If it is 4 to 5 years old, then
deduct it by 50%. That is, if someone's vehicle is
5 years old, then its
value has reduced by 50%. The main thing is that now this vehicle is worth
₹5000000, okay, even if you bought it for ₹
13000000, the rest is just an extra
cost. The price of the vehicle was ₹1 lakh,
its value inside the showroom was ₹1
lakh, when it was taken out of the showroom,
this price was calculated, so now its value has reduced to ₹500000.
Now the question arises that my
vehicle is 6 years old. Suppose someone has a
6 year old vehicle, then
how will you calculate its value? Its value now becomes your choice
brother.  You have to invest less than 50, that means less
than 50000. Now suppose the vehicle is 6 years old,
now if you want you can put its value at 48000 or
even 45000, that is
your choice, so how
easy it will be to buy this insurance.
Now I have told you almost all the points, what
is the main one, you just have to come here,
we have to take comprehensive insurance only,
we will select zero depreciation
along with insured declared value, we will
judge the value of our vehicle accordingly,
you take a screenshot of it, okay,
here in a way I have told you that
almost every year the value goes on decreasing by 10,
okay, so
select your IDV accordingly, and one more thing
comes in it, you have to understand, this is
no claim bonus, what does it mean, let's suppose
my insurance is for 00 or 00, let's
suppose my Activa is
insured for 00, okay, yes this year  If
I do not make any claim next year, then the
value of my vehicle will decrease, so the
insurance first thing is obvious it will be of
50 because my ID has also decreased, the
value has decreased, so the price of insurance will
also decrease, secondly if I do not make any claim in the first year then
I will get a no claim bonus, that is if
I did not make a claim then
I will get a discount for that, okay so
how much discount is this, suppose if
someone did not make a claim in the first year then he will get a
discount of 20, that is if he had taken it for 00 then he will get a
discount of ₹, along with that the
insurance also became a little cheaper, it
became 1150 because the value of my vehicle
decreased, subtract ₹ 40 from it, so
suppose if someone did not make a claim for 2 years then
he will get a no claim bonus of 25, whatever it was in the
first year, now
calculate it on 25, suppose in the third year if he did
not make a claim for three consecutive years then he will get a
discount of 35, if he did not take it for 4 years then it will be of
00, then it will be of 45  You will get it and if you do
not claim for 5 years continuously then you will
get a discount of 50 i.e. ₹ 6600
along with that the value of insurance will decrease, let's suppose at
that time ₹ 1000000, if you
reduce 600 then only
₹ 2000000 you can set it as per your wish in a minute,
they have so much software, did
you understand the matter, the main point is
that he will not tell you that you are getting no
claim bonus also, what about
you, most of you people also do it like this,
last year the
insurance of a car was of 12100, this year he did it for
1150, let's fix the price, there is no
problem even if you did not claim for 5 years,
suppose you did not claim for an auto or a bike for 5 years, have
you ever gone and asked that do I not get
no claim bonus, that is why
I am saying that within 2 minutes
when we can do something by ourselves
and it is so easy  It is such a thing that
even a fifth grader can
get two-wheeler insurance online. It
is so easy, then why do we go to shopkeepers nearby
and why do we need a person to
whom we pay extra money and ask him to
insure us. This is so easy
when the process is so simple, right? Apart from this, there is one
more thing called personal accident cover. I
mean, what do you call it, there is a link to Policy Bazaar. I will
also give you that in the description box.
If you want to get two-wheeler insurance for yourself
or want to get a new one or renew it, then
you can easily get it for yourself from there.
Right, there is one more thing called
personal accident cover. It is mandatory,
but a challan is also issued at
many places, at many places it is not issued,
but you should get personal accident
cover. For example, right now we
bought this for ₹ 714. Okay, on top of that, GST of ₹ 18 was levied at ₹
129. So, in total, I would have had to pay an insurance of ₹ 843.
If I had  I also take personal accident cover of ₹1 lakh, for example, suppose this person
is an Ekva, let's suppose he has a
driver, he has taken insurance for Ekva and also taken
personal accident cover of ₹15 lakh,
suppose tomorrow, whatever
XY is this person's active is hit
and it ends, the person is not there, then
in that case his family will also get ₹1 lakh
and in these cases, if
suppose his hands and legs are broken, eyesight is lost,
permanent disability occurs, then
in that case also his family will get 100% claim,
suppose if permanent disability occurs,
hands and legs are broken, then in that case also the family will get
100% claim of ₹15 lakh, so this thing is
a little good from the safety point of view, you should
take this, for example, it is
showing three
companies inside it, it is showing Chola, it is showing
Liberty, if you want to take any of them, it is
showing the price also, so if you want to take it,
you can also take this personal
Accident cover, okay, so these were all the
things, now we have seen everything,
now what is there in two wheeler insurance,
now let us see live once that
yes, how we can get two wheeler insurance for
ourselves in less than 1 minute,
now for getting two wheeler insurance from Policy Bazaar,
I have given you its link in the description box, as soon as
you click on that link,
some such interface will appear in front of us,
here first of all you have to
enter the number of your vehicle, whatever bike, scooter, whatever you have,
you have to enter its number and
below you have to click on view prices,
after that it will take some loading time,
okay, you have to stay on this page,
then some such interface will appear in front of you,
okay, here on the left side it is showing you
all the details, it is showing your vehicle
number, it is showing when it
is registered, from above you can select whether you
want to take third party, you can take third party, you can take
comprehensive, you can
take comprehensive, for example, suppose
I am ICICI  I will buy Lombard, okay,
I
click on the price option here, it
is showing me Rs. 735, after that it is
showing all the details, in whose name it
is registered, it is showing all the things, this
is Lombard from ICI, I have also selected the ID here
2550 because this
was a 2016 model
activa-i,
I have selected this also, so my
total amount becomes 1251, if suppose
I do not select this, okay, yes, for
personal accident cover, my
amount is Rs. 867, so this is your choice,
I will still select it, below
I just have to click on the Pay Secure option,
okay, it is
taking a little bit of loading time, after that on the next page
it is showing two-three options, suppose
I click on generate QR code here, then I don't have to do
anything, I
just open my phone from here, from
here I open my application, I just have to
scan it  Okay, sir,
this ₹2500000 from here,
I am doing this from my iMobile application,
as soon as I enter it from here, it becomes
₹1500000,
okay, sir, here it is asking
that if you have any other vehicle, then
give its reference, so here I
select that I do
not have any other vehicle, okay, sir, just here it is
saying that KYC is pending, I just have to
enter my PAN card number and date
of birth, so after entering PAN card and date of
birth, I
will click on complete KYC below, okay,
after entering these few details, my
policy has finally been booked, here
I have to click on download policy
and my two wheeler insurance  This has been
downloaded, you can just take a print out of it and
keep it in your Activa,
see all these details have come,
what do you say is my insurance for the next 1 year,
it has been done, see what a
simple process it was, such an easy process
for which we wander here and there, which we
can do in less than 1 minute,
so this entire
copy of the insurance policy has come to us,
you
can take a print out of it and keep it inside your vehicle, so this
was a very simple process, I hope you
found this video informative, for now this
is the end of the video, thanks for listening
and thank you all